So I'm now going to talk about five important hyperparameters for the training process.
이제 훈련 프로세스에 필요한 5개의 하이퍼파라미터에 대해 말씀드리죠
And some of these we've talked about briefly before.
이 중 일부는 전에 간단히 얘기한 적이 있죠
But many of these will be somewhat new to you unless you've worked in other data science projects of
하지만 대부분은 생소할 겁니다 이런 종류의 데이터 과학 프로젝트에서 일한 적이
this sort.
없다면요
And the first one I'll mention is epochs, which we did briefly mention some some time ago.
첫 번째는 에포치입니다 몇 번 짧게 언급했었죠
So epochs are referring to how many times are you going to go through your entire data set, uh, as
epoch는 훈련 과정의 일부로 전체 데이터 세트를 몇 번이나 검토할지를
part of the training process.
뜻해요
So you might imagine that when you're training, you take each of your training data points and you
여러분이 훈련할 때 각각의 훈련 데이터 포인트를 가지고 세트를
go through the set once and then you're done.
한 번 거치면 끝이라고 생각할 수 있죠
But in fact, it turns out that you can get more mileage by going back a second time and going through
하지만 사실 다시 돌아가서 훈련 데이터를 모델과 함께 다시 검토하면 더 많은 마일리지들을 얻을 수 있어요.
all of your training data again with your model.
Get in get get get it.
Now you might think, why?
왜냐고 궁금하시겠죠
Why does it help to go through a second time when the model already saw it once?
모델이 이미 한 번 봤는데 왜 다시 보려는 거죠?
So you're just giving it the same data a second time?
두 번째에도 같은 데이터를 주나요?
Well, remember when we go through the training optimization process involves going through each of
훈련 최적화 과정을 거치면서 이런 점들을 하나씩
these points and then making a very small step in the direction of making the model a little bit better,
짚어 보고 모델이 더 잘 보이게 작은 단계를 밟아요
shifting the weights in our in our Laura matrices a little tiny bit so that next time it does a bit
무게추를 조금씩 바꾸면 다음에는 더 잘 닦일 거예요
Um, so every time we go through all of the training data set, we have an opportunity to get a little
훈련 데이터 세트를 검토할 때마다 조금씩 향상될 기회가 있어요 비트 코일, 비트
tiny bit better.
코일, 비트 코일
Um, and presumably once it's gone through, once the model is now in a bit of a different state.
비트가 통과하고 나면 모델이 약간 다른 상태가 되겠죠
So when it sees it again, it can allow it to refine and do a little bit better.
비트를 다시 봤을 때 더 개선할 수 있어요
There is another reason why it often makes sense to have multiple epochs, and that comes down to batch
여러 단계가 필요한 또 다른 이유가 있습니다 바로 배치 크기인데요
The next hyperparameter batch size, is saying that often we don't take one data point and put it through
다음 hyperpaameter 배치 사이즈는 종종 하나의 데이터 포인트를 모델의 전방으로 보내 다음
the forward pass of the model to predict the next token, calculate the loss, and then go backwards
토큰을 예측하고 손실을 계산한 다음 되돌아가 손실된 금액의 단계별을
and figure out the gradients of how much does that loss?
계산하지 않는다는 것을 의미하죠
Is that affected by the different weights in the parameter in the model?
모델 내에서 다른 무게에 영향을 받는 건가요?
And then optimize the model by doing a little step in the right direction?
그런 다음 올바른 방향으로 작은 단계를 밟아 모델을 최적화하는 거죠
Uh, it sometimes makes sense to do that at the same time with a bunch of data points together.
동시에 여러 데이터 포인트를 합치는 게 좋을 때도 있어요
Like often you pick a four or 8 or 16 and you do it together for for all 16.
4개나 8개, 16개를 골라서 16개 전부를 같이 하는 거죠
One reason for doing that is, is performance, that it means that you can just get through everything
그렇게 하는 이유 중 하나는 성능입니다. 모든 것을 빠르게 할 수 있다는 것을 의미하죠. Get
faster.
it.
You can do it all together.
다 같이 하면 돼요
If you can fit 16 data points on your GPU, then that's a good thing to do.
GPU 데이터 포인트가 16개면 좋은 거죠
There are some other reasons why it might actually be better to do it in batches, than to do it step
단계별로 하는 것보다 여러 번에 나눠서 하는 게 더 좋은 이유가
by step.
있어요
Um, uh, but but, uh, but the basic reason is for performance.
하지만 기본 이유는 실적 때문이에요
When you do multiple epochs with each epoch, it's typical that you resort or you juggle up all of the
한 가지 시대로 여러 가지 시도를 할 땐 모든 시도를 한 번에 성공하는 게 일반적이죠
So they're different batches, different sets of these 16 data points that the model sees with each
즉, 모델은 각 발생기에서 16개의 데이터 포인트를 다른 배치로 보게 되는
of your epochs.
것이죠
So actually in some ways the data is different for each of these epochs because it's seeing a different
사실 데이터는 어떤 면에서 각 발생에 따라 다릅니다 발생을 거치면서
sample of your data points as it goes through them.
다른 데이터 포인트의 샘플을 보기 때문이죠
And that's another reason why multiple epochs can be good.
그래서 다양한 시대가 좋은 거예요
Now there's one very common technique which is to at the end of each epoch, you typically save your
아주 보편적인 기술이 하나 있는데 각 에포크의 끝에서 모델을 저장하는 거예요
And it's quite common to run a bunch of epochs and then test how your model performed at the end of
여러 신세계를 실행한 후 각 신세계 끝에서 모델이 어떻게 수행했는지 테스트하는
each of those epochs, and what you often find is that the model was getting better and better as it
건 흔한 일입니다 그런데 그 모델은 각 신세계에서 더 많이 배울수록 더 좋아지곤 합니다
learned more and more in each epoch, but then you reach a certain point where the model starts to overfit,
하지만 지난 시간에 얘기했던 것처럼 모델이 지나치게 충족되는 지점에 도달하면
which we talked about last time, where it starts to get so used to seeing this training data that it
이 훈련 데이터에 너무 익숙해져서 그 훈련 데이터만을
starts to solve just for exactly that training data.
위해 해결하기 시작하죠
And then when you test it, the performance gets worse because it's not expecting points outside its
그리고 테스트했을 때 성능이 더 나빠집니다 훈련 데이터 세트 외의 점수는 기대하지 않기
training data set.
때문이죠
So you start to see like better, better, better, better, worse, worse, worse.
점점 좋아지고 좋아지고 나빠지고 나빠지는 게 보여요
And then the results get continually worse.
결과는 계속 나빠지기만 하죠 Get it
And what you do is you run this and you quite simply pick the epoch which gave you the best model,
이 프로그램을 실행하면서 최고의 모델과 결과를 제공한 이포크를 고르면
the best outcome.
되죠
And that's the one that you consider the results of your training.
훈련의 결과로 생각하는 거죠
That's the version of the fine tuned model and that's what you take forwards.
그게 미세 튜닝 모델의 버전이고 그걸 앞으로 가져가는 거죠
So it's common to run a larger number of epochs and then use that kind of testing to pick which one
더 많은 이전화를 실행해 어떤 모델이 최선인지 고르는 테스트가
was your best model.
일반적이죠
With that, I will pause and continue with these parameters in the next video.
다음 비디오에서 이 매개 변수들을 잠시 멈추고 계속할게요